JAYIT SAHA

@ jayitsaha@gmail.com

+917595093227

♥ Kolkata, West Bengal, India

in linkedin/jayit-saha

ricksaha2000

ABOUT ME

An avid software developer, data scientist and a researcher. I am a Data Scientist II at Walmart in their Data Strategy and Insights team. I am currently a peer reviewer at Knowledge and Information Systems Journal (Springer). I am the holder of the very prestigious NTU India Connect Fellowship with an acceptance rate of 0.0001%. I am also a Google HashCode World Finalist (World's Biggest and Most Prestigious Coding Competition) and the only student team (World Rank 30) out of the 3 qualified Indian teams. I have also been awarded with World's most reputed and highly competitive research Internship, Mitacs Globalink Research Internship at University of Guelph. I have won several International and National hackathons, and published 4 research papers in Springer and Scopus indexed journals. Additionally, three more papers are in review. I strive to make products, which tend to address and efficiently solve major societal issues, using Artificial Intelligence and Complex Algorithmic solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist II

Walmart Global Tech

🛗 Jul 2022 - Present

- Pangalore, India
- Working as a Data Scientist at Walmart Global Tech India

Data Science Intern

Walmart Global Tech

m Jan 2022 - Jul 2022

- Pangalore, India
- Working as a Data Scientist on two simultaneous products in the Data Strategy and Insights Team at Walmart

Research Intern

Nanyang Technological University Singapore

Marg 2021 - Dec 2021

- Singapore
- Determining the Impact of Public Sentiment on Bitcoin Depth Pipelining Fine-Tuned FinBERT and SenticNet

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Django, React.js, Node.js, ML/DL JAVA, PostgreSQL, NLP, OpenCV, RASA React Native, PyTorch, C++, Tensorflow



AWARDS & POSITIONS HELD

- Google HashCode World Finalist: International Rank 30
- India Connect@NTU Research Internship Awardee-Fall 2021
- 2nd Rank Holder Nationally at Dare2Compete Awards 2022 under D2C Competitive E-School Leader 2022 Category
- Featured in Forbes India April 2022 Edition for The Best Engineering Student Category
- The Economic Times Campus Stars Class of 2021
- Winner of Rakutens' Flagship Hackathon Rakathon '22
- Winner of Optum Stratethon Season 3 International Hackathon
- Winner of Route Mobile RAPID International Hackathon
- Winner of Hackathon Atmanirbhar Bharat 59 National Hackathon.
- First Runners Up Optum Stratethon S02 International Hackathon
- First Runners Up of Women Techies '21
- National Finalist in Myntra HackerRamp 2021 (Top 7)
- Second Runners Up of Weavy Build Tomorrow Hackathon
- Second Runners Up and Winner of Ren Track of DevJams' 21
- Top 10 Special Mention Teams at **Hack of PI@PI-WOT** Hackathon
- Core Commitee Marketing Team for Vibrance and TechnoVIT

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science and Engineering)

Vellore Institute of Technology

2018- Pursuing

♦ Chennai

• CGPA: 9.42

PROJECTS

GROC4ALL

 (Winner - HAB 59) A Multi-Vendor grocery website designed for the old embedded with a facial biometric and automated grocery ordering chatbot, Genetic Algorithm to give Local vendors a fair chance and a customer sentiment analysis system.

WCDVA

A react based mobile application for waste classification and detection with trash volumetric analysis using YOLO, Mask RCNN, SFM and Point Cloud architecture. The YOLO backbone framework, with the EfficientNet learners, was used for the real time trash classification pipeline. The volumetric model uses SFM for accurate pointcloud structures for the waste pile, the volume of which was processed using STL and trimesh python libraries.

I-PARK

 An intelligent parking system Algorithm for smart parking of vehicles in areas based on shortest distance to free space available. To avoid illegal parking with the help of strategically aligned cameras, using image processing and car annotations.

Precision Agriculture System

 Crop Recommendation system to facilitate to farmers regarding the type of crop, which would be most beneficial towards the soil based on previous crops sown and environmental conditions, using the WSN IOT devices, with weed detection using DRONES.

MEDBAY

(Runners Up- Optum Stratethon S2) An AI based system for intelligent diet prediction packed with a Medical Diagnostic Chatbot, Heart
Rate Estimator Via Webcam, Customized Diet Planner and Multi User
Yoga Application

PUBLICATIONS

- Al Crop Predictor and Weed Detector Using Wireless Technologies: A Smart Application for Farmers (SPRINGER)
- Design of Waste Management System Using Ensemble Neural Networks (SCOPUS)
- Review paper on Sleep Apnea Detection using AI (SCOPUS)
- Developing A Transdisciplinary Citizen Science Tool For Experiential Learning In Undergraduate Education: Squirrel Life In A Nutshell
- Adoption of Precision Agriculture by Detecting and Spraying Herbicide using UAV (SCOPUS)
- Al techniques in solar cells and solar energy applications (SCOPUS)

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCES

MITACS Globalink Research Intern

University of Guelph

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Q Guelph, Ontario, Canada

 Research Intern - University of Guelph - Guelph, Canada, working on React Native project with a SpringBoot, Hibernate and Lombok backend.

Peer Reviewer

Knowledge and Information Systems (KAIS)

Mov 2021 - Present

Springer

• Invited to be a peer reviewer in the very prestigious Springer Indexed Journal, Knowledge and Information Systems (KAIS) with an Impact Factor of 3.161

Programme Representative BTECH CSE

Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai

Sep 2021 - Present

▼ Tamil Nadu, India

• Selected as Programme Representative in my Senior year, representing the entire Computer Science and Engineering branch.

Freelancer

Norman Networking

m Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

Canada

• To develop a Scouting Platform for the National Canadian Rugby Teams, officially contracted by Toronto Arrows Rugby Club, with a base pay of 3,000 CAD.

Software Developer Intern

Tech Mahindra

m Oct 2020 - Mar 2021

Pune, India

• Implementing Random Forest and Neural Networks, to develop face authenticated web based application, specific to ecommerce sites, coupled with chatbot system and computer vision application integration.

University Teaching Assistant

Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai

▼ Tamil Nadu, India

Selected as the University Teaching Assistant for the course JAVA Programming (CSE1007/SWE1007)

Software Developer Intern

Gewissen Digital Services

🛗 Jul 2020 - Sept 2020

• Revolving around a full web application using React, Node and Firebase. Handling security amidst various user roles and a clean and smooth interface design being primary aims.

Data Analyst and Full Stack Developer

Yakkay Technologies.

May 2020 - Oct 2020

♥ Chennai, India

• A professional internship which revolved around making a full stack application integrated with pipe-lining of huge amounts of corporate data and their respective analysis, hence rendering a complete product.

Full Stack Engineer

Bizmarvel

m Dec 2019 - Apr 2020

Switzerland

• I was a part of this organization for over a period of 4 months. In this internship i worked on three different projects, all based on Django. I tried to make as smooth and flexible Ul's, hence developing full end to end products.